<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peter Heisig Software</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/</link><description>Recent content on Peter Heisig Software</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><atom:link href="https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Legal Disclosure</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/imprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/imprint/</guid><description>Information in accordance with Section 5 TMG Peter Heisig
Deubener Straße 6
01159 Dresden
Contact Information Phone: 0351 217 163 76
E-Mail: peter@heisig.rocks
Internet: https://peter.heisig.rocks
Disclaimer Accountability for content The contents of our pages have been created with the utmost care. However, we cannot guarantee the contents&amp;rsquo; accuracy, completeness or topicality. According to statutory provisions, we are furthermore responsible for our own content on these web pages. In this matter, please note that we are not obliged to monitor the transmitted or saved information of third parties, or investigate circumstances pointing to illegal activity.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/privacy-policy/</guid><description>Personal data (usually referred to just as &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; below) will only be processed by us to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.
Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;ldquo;GDPR&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;processing&amp;rdquo; refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.</description></item></channel></rss>