<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peter Heisig - Software Consulting and Development</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/</link><description>Recent content on Peter Heisig - Software Consulting and Development</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Neo4j Graph View Editor</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/posts/neo4j-graph-view-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/posts/neo4j-graph-view-editor/</guid><description>TL;DR The Neo4j1 Browser2 is a great tool for querying a graph and comes with a well designed user interface that supports data visualization and iterative exploration. But in terms of manipulation, the user has to write Cypher3-queries, respectively knowing the language in detail. I forked the GitHub-Project4 and extended the user interface for the sake of visual data manipulation. This allow rapid model prototyping and evolution without querying the graph with Cypher.</description></item><item><title>Thunderbird Taiga Integration</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/posts/thunderbird-taiga-integration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/posts/thunderbird-taiga-integration/</guid><description>As described in the Getting Things Done methodology we have to cope with a large amount of incoming information; E-mails are outdated, but still heavily used. They are trapped in our client software, only transferable by copy and paste. Thus we need a way to import those into our favorite project management system to actually get things done.
Working with Taiga and Thunderbird for quite a while now, I managed to write a thunderbird extension for this very purpose.</description></item><item><title>Legal Disclosure</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/imprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/imprint/</guid><description>Information in accordance with Section 5 TMG Peter Heisig
Deubener Straße 6
01159 Dresden
Contact Information Phone: 0351 217 163 76
E-Mail: peter@heisig.rocks
Internet: https://peter.heisig.rocks
Disclaimer Accountability for content The contents of our pages have been created with the utmost care. However, we cannot guarantee the contents&amp;rsquo; accuracy, completeness or topicality. According to statutory provisions, we are furthermore responsible for our own content on these web pages. In this matter, please note that we are not obliged to monitor the transmitted or saved information of third parties, or investigate circumstances pointing to illegal activity.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peter.heisig.rocks/en/privacy-policy/</guid><description>Personal data (usually referred to just as &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo; below) will only be processed by us to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.
Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;ldquo;GDPR&amp;rdquo;), &amp;ldquo;processing&amp;rdquo; refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.</description></item></channel></rss>